mspca.org 2019-05-16

# Privacy Policy • MSPCA-Angell

The Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (the MSPCA-Angell) cares about protecting the privacy and integrity of the information you provide us when you use our websites, including but not limited to (mspca.org, angell.org, support.mspca.org). This privacy policy explains how we collect, process, share, store, and protect any data and information you provide us while using our websites. By using our websites and/or submitting personal data through our website, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy and you expressly consent to the collection and use of your personal data in accordance with this privacy policy. **If you have any questions about the below or wish to change your communication preferences with us, please email webeditor @mspca.org**.

### What information do we collect about you?

Our registration forms, surveys, and/or e-stores require users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information, format preference (HTML vs. Text), interests, and similar information. We do not store sensitive information from our visitors, such as credit card or social security numbers.

We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users’ movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

### How will we use the information we collect about you?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content that is most relevant to you
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you
  * To allow us to better serve you in responding to your requests
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To quickly process your transactions
  * To send periodic emails regarding our work
  * For follow up after initial correspondence

### How long do we keep your information?

We hold on to information that you provide us for the period allowable by law where we have a justifiable business need to do so.  You can request the deletion of your personal data at any time and all requests will be honored in accordance with applicable laws.

### Sharing your information

We may share your personal information with third party vendors and other service providers as needed to carry out services on our behalf as necessary for the operation of the MSPCA’s website. This may include identifying and serving targeted advertisements, billing, marketing, data analytics support, order fulfillment, and payment processing. We only work with reputable vendors who comply with applicable privacy laws

When you make a donation to the MSPCA, it is possible that your name may be on some mailing lists shared with other reputable organizations. As a donor, you may request to have your name removed from these mailing lists. To remove your name from mailing lists shared with other organizations, please email webeditor @mspca.org with your full name, mailing address and a sentence requesting removal from the MSPCA shared list.

### Marketing

The MSPCA-Angell uses remarketing to display ads across the internet, in particular on the Google Display Network and Facebook, based on what parts of our website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your web browser. This cookie does not in any way identify you or give access to your computer or mobile device. This use of remarketing allows us to tailor our messages to only display ads that are relevant to you. If you do not wish to see ads from the MSPCA-Angell, you can opt out by visiting [Google’s Ad settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) and/or [Facebook’s Ad settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen).

We may work with social media companies (primarily Facebook) to show you interest-based ads to you or to your friends through Facebook’s Custom Audience Tool. This tool allows us to personalize our ads based on you or your friends’ interactions with MSPCA-Angell. We do not share personal information about you with Facebook, but we share a hashed email address or phone number which allows Facebook to identify our advertising audience based on the information that Facebook collects from its users. If you do not want to receive interest-based ads on Facebook, you can adjust your ad preferences through your [Facebook settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen).

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact webeditor @mspca.org.

### Your choices about your information

**We will always honor your requests to modify your communication preferences with us.** We respect your privacy and recognize that you may wish to limit our communications with you. We may send you emails or mailings in the future to inform you of update you on MSPCA news or giving opportunities. If you choose not to receive any further communications from us, you may opt out by emailing webeditor@mspca.org with your full name, mailing address and a sentence requesting removal from the MSPCA mailing list.

For EEA users or similar international areas: You also have the right to access your personal data, the right to request we erase your personal data, the right to correct it, and the right to request that we stop processing your data. To exercise these rights, please contact webeditor @mspca.org and let them know you plan to exercise your rights under GDPR.

### Cookies

Our Site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our Site. Cookies are pieces of information that some Web sites transfer to the computer that is browsing that Web site and are used for record-keeping purposes at many Web sites. Use of cookies makes Web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular Web site and to make sure you don’t see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function properly when you view them, but it is very unlikely.

### How we protect your data

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

All transactions on this website are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

All information provided to MSPCA-Angell is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our Site that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of MSPCA-Angell. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. Donations processed on this website are VeriSign Secured.

### A note to users outside the United States

If you are a non-US user of our website, by accessing our site and providing us with your personal data, you agree that your personal data will be processed for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy. Your personal data will be processed in the United States, where laws regarding processing of personal data may differ from the laws in your country. By providing us with your data, you consent to this transfer. For further information please contact webeditor@mspca.org

### A note about children

We do not intentionally collect personal data from website visitors that are under the age of 13. We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13. If a child under 13 submits personal information to our website and we learn about it, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible.

### Other websites

Our Site contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another Web site for which the MSPCA-Angell has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.

### Changes to our privacy policy

This privacy policy is updated on a regular basis. If there are changes to this policy, we will post those changes here. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting. The last time this policy was updated was May 15, 2018.

### How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact webeditor @mspca.org or at the address below:

Web Editor

350 South Huntington Ave

Boston, MA 02130

USA
